Guide to the Nicholas School Master's Projects, 1933-2005 UA.18.01.0003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Nicholas School Master's Projects
1933-2007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Nicholas School of the Environment and Earth Sciences (Duke University)
UA.18.01.0003
82.5 Linear Feet
As of 2005, the Nicholas School of the Environment and Earth Sciences at Duke University offers two master's degree programs: Master of Environmental Management (MEM) and Master of Forestry (MF). Both degree programs require students complete a master's project that presents an in-depth or quantitative analysis of a problem related to the students' particular focus area. Collection contains printed, bound master's projects. Materials range in date 1933-2005. Master's Projects for 2005 are held in the Nicholas School office. English.
2400 Items
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Current year stored on-site. Previous years in off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Nicholas School Master's Projects was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 2005, 2008.
The Nicholas School Master's Projects 2003-2004 were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 2007.
The Nicholas School Master's Projects 1933-1997 were received by the University Archives as a transfer from the Biological and Environmental Sciences Library in 2008.
Historical Note
As of 2005, the Nicholas School of the Environment and Earth Sciences at Duke University offers two master's degree programs: Master of Environmental Management (MEM) and Master of Forestry (MF). Both degree programs require students complete a master's project that presents an in-depth or quantitative analysis of a problem related to the students' particular focus area.
Collection Overview
Collection contains printed, bound master's projects. Materials range in date 1933-2005. Master's Projects for 2005 (boxes 15-16) are held in the Nicholas School office. Box 14 ends with Zollett 2004.
Arrangement note
Master's Projects are arranged in chronological order by year, then alphabetically by author's last name.
Forest management; Environmental management; Nicholas School of the Environment and Earth Sciences (Duke University); Duke University -- Students; Nicholas School of the Environment and Earth Sciences (Duke University)
- 1933-1939 -- Master's Projects, 1 boxes
  - 1933-1943 (Box 17)
- 1940-1949 --Master's Projects, 5 boxes
  - 1933-1943 (Box 17)
  - 1946-1947 Mills (Box 18)
  - 1947- Ralston-1948 Pomeroy (Box 19)
  - 1948 Reed-1949 Ralston (Box 20)
  - 1949 Rogers-1950 Wycoff (Box 21)
- 1950-1969 -- Master's Projects, 4 boxes
  - 1949 Rogers-1950 Wycoff (Box 21)
  - 1950 Zirkle-1951 Powell (Box 22)
  - 1951 Smith-1953 Markley (Box 23)
  - 1955 Haeussler-1957 Hitchings (Box 24)
  - 1957 Hug-1970 Elliot (Box 25)
- 1970-1979 -- Master's Projects, 4 boxes
  - 1957 Hug-1970 Elliot (Box 25)
  - 1970 McLaughlin-1976 Wilson (Box 26)
  - 1977 Coffey-1979 Croxton (Box 27)
  - 1979 Doubs-1980 Brown (Box 28)
- 1980-1989 -- Master's Projects, 12 boxes
  - 1979 Doubs-1980 Brown (Box 28)
  - 1980 Conklin-1980 Zoephil (Box 29)
  - 1981 Berger-1981 Ruzsa (Box 30)
  - 1981 Spath-1982 Thayer (Box 31)
  - 1982 Ticknor-1983 Paige (Box 32)
  - 1983 Quin-1984 Smith (Box 33)
  - 1984 Sontheimer-1985 Shrestha (Box 34)
  - 1985 Spollen-1986 Stout (Box 35)
  - 1986 Sullivan-1987 Smith (Box 36)
  - 1987 Spellman-1988 Moyer (Box 37)
  - 1988 Ompal-1989 Lahm (Box 38)
  - 1989 Mahon-1990 Dreyfors (Box 39)
- 1990-1999 -- Master's Projects, 22 boxes
  - 1989 Mahon-1990 Dreyfors (Box 39)
  - 1990 Durin-1990 Tippert (Box 40)
  - 1990 Valetine-1991 Howard (Box 41)
  - 1991 Hudson-1991 Vilem (Box 42)
  - 1991 Vise-1992 Gerlaugh (Box 43)
  - 1992 Gerzon-1992 Rosner (Box 44)
  - 1992 Samuels-1993 Chazal Box pulled for cataloging. Contents unavailable until cataloging is complete. (Box 45)
  - 1993 Clevelan-1993 Seiberling (Box 46)
  - 1993 Sharma-1994 Cizmas (Box 47)
  - 1994 Clark-1994 Milone (Box 48)
  - 1994 Munishi-1995 Andrell (Box 49)
  - 1995 Archer-1995 Knipling (Box 50)
  - 1995 Knatt-1995 Zimmerling (Box 51)
  - 1996 Abadia-1996 Herz (Box 52)
  - 1996 Hester-1996 Murakami (Box 53)
  - 1996 Nelsen-1996 Welton (Box 54)
  - 1996 West-1997 Grant (Box 55)
  - 1997 Haddad-1997 Oswald (Box 56)
  - 1997 Palumbo-1997 Zipp (Box 57)
  - 1998 Abedin-1998 Guevara (Box 58)
  - 1998 Gutowski-1998 Olnger (Box 59)
  - 1998 Peterson-1998 Zukerberg (Box 60)
- 1999 -- Master's Projects, 3 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Box 1 has been pulled for cataloging (May 2013). Contents will be unavailable until cataloging is complete.
  - Anderson, Brian Pitner: Involvement of CYP1A2 in the Metabolism and Toxicity of Bromodichloromethane (BDCM), 1999 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Elise Driscoll: Science & Decision Making at the Environmental Protection Agency, Region IX, San Francisco, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Maren E.: Goose Creek Urban Stream Restoration Project: A Baseline Study, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Anley, Melissa Beatriz: Harnessing Cyberspace: A Study of Perceptions, Utility and Customer Satisfaction with the U.S.E.P.A., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Keith D.: Historic Preservation on Dynamic Coastlines: To Move or Not to Move?, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Babcock, Scott R.: Light Pollution and the Night Sky; an Emerging Resource Management Problem for the National Park Service., 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Joseph Jeremy: Compositional Analysis of the Cane Creek Watershed, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bayer, Taryn Frost: The Effect of CO2 on the Growth Rates of Loblolly Pine Trees, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Blackmore, Laura L.: Quaternary Lake-Level Fluctuations at Puno Bay, Lake Titicaca, Peru: Regional and Global Climate Implications, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bohensky, Erin L.: Road Mortality of the Zanzibar Red Colobus Monkey (Procolobus kirkii): Implications of Landscape Pattern in an African Forest Reserve, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bolduc, Joel F.: Maximizing Profits to Protect the Environment Pollution Prevention at a Textile Printing Facility, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Boren, Sarah A.: Analysis of Potential Barriers to the Restorative Economy Vision; Case Studies with the US Economy, the Raw Milk Industry and an Individual Dairy Farm, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Boyer, Stanley M.: Teleworking: How Does this Traffic Congestion and Air Pollution Reducing Program Offer Added Value for Corporations?, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bramlage, J. Catherine: Supplemental Environmental Projects: An Analysis of the Use of SEP's in Environmental Enforcement Actions, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Bressler, David W.: Influence of Land Use and Stream Habitat on Macroinvertebrate Communities of the Henrys Fork Watershed in Idaho and Wyoming, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Anna L.: An Analysis of the Environmental Variables Associated with Two Protected Forest Communities in Washington State, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Burroughs, Elizabeth P.: Regeneration Ecology of Baldcypress on the Roanoke River Floodplain, North Carolina, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Butry, David T.: Tropical Forest Conservation in Ruteng Park; Welfare Implications of a Command and Control Strategy, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Buxton, Andrea: Assessing the Impact of Methyl Tertiary-Butyl Ether (MTBE) on Drinking Water Supplies in Lake Tahoe, California, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Chen, Ming-chun: Management and Monitoring of Dengue Vectors in Taiwan, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Joshua Gabriel: Silvicultural Strides Toward the Sustainable Management of Mahogany (Swietenia macrophylla King) in the Rio Bravo Conservation and Management Area of Belize, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Colborn, Katherine: Interactions Between Humans and Bottlenose Dolphins, Tursiops Truncates, near Panama City, Florida, 1999 (Box 1)
  - DeSanto, Elizabeth Maxwell: The Effectiveness of the Agreement on the Conservation of Small Cetaceans of the Baltic and North Seas, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Dickson, Alisa: The Effects of Disturbances on Community Succession in Cladium Areas of WCA 2B of the Florida Everglades, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Dorley, Peter J.: Adsorption of Hydroxy Pyridines and Quinolines onto Titanium Dioxide, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Forney, William M.: The Volumetric Runoff and Erosion Model; A Landscape Perspective of Erosion and Land Use in the Upper Truckee Watershed, Lake Tahoe, California, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Fritz, Lesley: Creating Another Kalundborg: Case Study of Industrial Ecology in Research Triangle Park, NC, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Gelbard, Jonathan L.: Multiple-Scale Causes of Exotic Plant Invasions in Rangelands of the Colorado Plateau and Great Basin, USA, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Gere, Jessica R.: Shellfish Sanitation in Eastern North Carolina: A Proposal for Change, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Good, Caroline: A Conservation Plan for Protecting Sea Turtle Nesting Beaches at the East End of St. Croix, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Goodman, Kimberley T.: A Site Conservation Plan for the Vanishing Rivers, Central Idaho, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Gray, Charlotte D.: A Spatial Analysis of Bottlenose Dolphins, Tursiops, Truncates, and Shrimp Trawling Activity in the Gulf of Mexico, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Gurtman, Sarah: Analysis of the Use of Spotter Aircraft in the Atlantic Bluefin Tuna Fishery, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Guzman, Greta G.: Predicting Tropical Deforestation: A Case Study in Rio Branco, Acre of Brazil, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Hale, Rhea K.: The National Expansion of Startrack Issues Regarding the Delegation of Environmental Compliance Oversight, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Heiner, Michael G.: Habitat Use by Rocky Mountain Sheep on the Yellowstone Northern Range, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Hofmockel, Kirsten: Effects of Hydrologic Management Decisions on Marsh Structure in Water Conservation Area 2A of the Everglades, Florida, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Hopkins, Susan E.: An Examination of Breeding Bird Communities in the North Carolina Sandhills, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Hunt, Rhonda: An Initial Marketing and Distribution Study of the City of Raleigh's Municipal Biosolids, pH Plus+, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Ikemoto, Nao: A Sensitivity Analysis of a Thermal Power Plant Project in Developing Countries, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Ivker, Julie: Ecotourists and Handicrafts: Purchase Behavior by Visitors to the Peruvian Amazon, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Nils Anders Christian: A Landscape Level Monitoring Plan for the Forested Floodplain Communities of the Lower Roanoke River Basin in North Carolina, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Joscelyn, Tyler Q.: Drinking Water Survey and Recommendations for a Rural Community, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Kannler, Kathleen Ann: Water Quality at Four Boston Harbor Beaches: A Predictive Measure to Beach Closures, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Karousakis, Katia T.: Economic Incentive Policies to Reduce Pollution Emissions from Vehicles: The Case for Vehicle Characteristics Taxes, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Kester, Jessica S.: The Development of an Interpretive Program at Lime Kiln Point State Park, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Koniuto, James S.: Development of a Probability (Bayes) Network Model for the Management of Nitrogen in the Neuse river Basin of Eastern North Carolina, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Kool, Johnathan: A Baseline Assessment of Selected Biological Species and Physical Environmental Factors in the Rachel Carson Estuarine Research Reserve, 1999 (Box 2)
  - LaForge, Ashley Alexandra: Waste Water Management Districts: An Alternative to Public Sewers for Rural Communities, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Link, Rick T.: Assessment of Cumulative Impacts in Hydropower Relicensing, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Lobeira, Santiago: Environmental Strategy to Manage Hazardous Wastes in the Telecommunications Industry. Case Study: Using Sprint's GIS to Manage Spent Lead-Acid Batteries, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Lovett, Crystal G.: Environmental and Economic Implications of Tree Protection Ordinances in the Research Triangle Region of North Carolina, 1999 (Box 2)
  - McKinstry, Sara J.: Scientists are from Mars, Journalists are from Venus: Marine Scientists and the Media in Environmental Education, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Miller, Tancred: Land-Use Planning under CAMA: Implications for the Commercial Fishing Industry in Carteret County, North Carolina, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Minnemeyer, Susan L.: Reducing Barriers to Mahogany Regeneration in Belize: Factors Affecting Germination, Seedling Survival, and Insect Attack, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Mislivets, Maureen: Optimizing Land Management Strategies Using Site and Regional Scale Information: A Case Study for Rifle Ridge Farm, Highland County, VA, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Moesel, Sharon M.: A Fishery Management Plan for the Shellfish Fishery in Core Sound, NC, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Moorman, Randall S.: Protected Areas and Local Community Relations: A Case Study at La Selva Biological Station, Costa Rica, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Murray, Kimberly T.: Spatial and Temporal Heterogeneity in Bycatch Rates of Harbor Porpoises in the Gulf of Maine: Implications for the Design of Marine Reserves, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Myers, C. Jordan: Development of Vegetation in a Created Wetland: The Effect of Substrate, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Nowicki, ReNae S.: Prioritization of Chesapeake Bay Watersheds for Ecological Improvement through Wetland Restoration, Enhancement and Protection, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Okada, Tomoyuki: Nutrient Trading Program in the Tar-Pamlico River and Command and Control System in the Neuse River, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Parson, Tiffany Ann Seibold: Does Maternal Fluoranthene Exposure Provide Photo-Protection in the Offspring of the Killifish (fundulus heteroclitus)?, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Pearlman, Leslie C.: Barriers and Beyond: Subsurface Containment and Monitoring Systems, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Pickler, Kristopher A.: The Increasing Role of Offshore Aquaculture in Ocean Management, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Popot, Stephanie P.: Application of Different Methodologies of Evaluation to a Forestry Development Project in Poland, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Quarterman, Steven J.: Conservation Guidelines for Colonial Beach-Nesting Birds on the Barrier Islands of North Carolina, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Rao, Leela E.: Changes in Abundance of Seagrass and Algae in a Pacific Northwest Estuary, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Rodriguez, Denise M.: Cost Benefit Analysis in Chile: 'Cascada Chile' Project, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Rosenberg, Sarah A.: Practical Applications of Ecotourism to Avian Conservation in the Neotropics, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Rothenberg, Jason A.: Sustainable Dive Tourism in Egypt's RAS Mohammed National Park, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Salem, Joseph Alexander: Green Power and its Potential as a Viable Energy Source: A Texas Case Study, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Sampson, Daniel W.: Assessment of Long-Term Land Use and Vegetation Change in the Albemarle-Pamlico Watershed Using NOAA AVHRR Satellite Data, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Sayoc, Marico: The Regulatory Process Governing Dredge Disposal: A Retrospective Case Study of Moss Landing Harbor, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Schreifels, Jeremy: Corporate Carbon: A General Framework for Calculating Corporate Greenhouse Emissions, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Selberg, Carrie D.: Environmental Variations and Low Oxygen in the Neuse River; Responses of Crabs and Crabbers, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Shoch, David Taylor: An Ecological and Economic Evaluation of Railroad Tie Harvest in the Ejido Xpichil, Quintana Roo, Mexico, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Shoffler, Sarah M.: The Development of a Marine Conservation District to Enhance Fisheries in the US Virgin Islands, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Shoji, Noriko L.: Geospatial Analysis of Commercial Trawl Effort within the Olympic Coast National Marine Sanctuary, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Shurna, David J.: The Socioeconomic Impact of Community Conservation Initiatives: A Case Study in the Pacaya-Samiria National Reserve, Peru, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Siebert, Cynthia: Developing an Effective Water Supply Demand Management Strategy in the Lower Colorado River Basin, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Sklad, Elizabeth A.: A Land Management Plan for Smith's Island, Bermuda, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Smid, Christopher: Reforestation of Degraded Agriculture Land with Native Tree Species in the Buffer Zone of the Calakmul Biosphere Reserve, Campeche, Mexico, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Smith, Darcie P.: An Examination of Mercury Contamination in the Environment, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Smith, Kristopher S.: Changing Traditions; An Economic Comparison Between the Norwegian Whaling and Whale-Watching Industries, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Sobti, Mayuri V.: The Land and Water Conservation Fund Prioritizing Federal Land Acquisitions for Biological Conservation, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Solomon, Hilary: The Potential Utility of Phytoremediation in Oregon and Washington, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Sussman, Sheryl: Using GIS to Evaluate the Potential for Wetlands to Improve Water Quality in the Nanticoke River Watershed, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Szymczak, Shannon Rider: Buying the Jocassee Gorges: State Park, Game Land or Both? A Case Study of North Carolina's Efforts to Establish the First State Park West of Asheville, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Takimoto, Asako: Analysis of Forest Resource Management for Conservation and Community Development; Care International Project in Indonesia, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Tansey, Heather: The Economic Impacts of Sediment and Sedimentation on Electric Utilities, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Thomson, Allison M.: Modeling the Response of Physical Ocean Processes to Climate Change, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Williams, Kimberlee C.: A Population Viability Analysis of Rough-Leaf Loosestrife and Venus Flytrap in the Green Swamp Preserve, NC, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Wu, Hsin-Jung: Implementation of ISO 14001 Environmental Management System: A Case Study on Incineration Plants in Taiwan, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Yellin, Anna: Monitoring Avian Health and Disease for Conservation Management, 1999 (Box 3)
- 2000 -- Master's Projects, 4 boxes
  - Anderson, Sloan K.: An Analysis of Stakeholder Perspectives and Best Management Practices for the Florida Aquaculture Industry, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Armstrong, Charles S., Jr.: Reproductive Success of Red-Cockaded Woodpecker Clusters on Sandy Island, South Carolina, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Baehr, Carsten H.: Statistical Evaluation of the UTAB Database for Use in Terrestrial Nontarget Organism Risk Assessment, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Barfield, Wayne A.: An Analysis of Water Quality on Three Forested Watersheds in Randolph County, West Virginia, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Bartee, Margaret: Perchloroethylene and Urban Air Quality: Is Our Nation's Health Getting Taken to the Cleaners?, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Beamish, Sarah Starr: Olema Creek Watershed Management Plan: Protecting and Restoring Coho Salmon and Steelhead Trout, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Beardsley, Kate E.: Fish Respiratory Responses to Hypoxia in the Neuse River., 2000 (Box 3)
  - Bell, Joel T.: Preliminary Characterization and Analysis of Selected Artificial Warm-Water Refugia and Their Use by the Florida Manatee, Trichechus manatus latirostris, on the East Coast of Florida, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Berlin, Daniel J.: Determination of the Hydrologic Properties of a Forested Slope Wetland Bloch, Phillip North Carolina Non-Native Plant Survey: Lessons for Monitoring, Management and Damage Assessments., 2000 (Box 3)
  - Bloch, Philip Leo: North Carolina Non-Native Plant Survey: Lessons for Monitoring, Management and Damage Assessments, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Bohart, Barbara: From Private to Preserved: Landowner Motivations to Donate Real Estate Interests, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Brewster, David B.: End-User Financing of Solar Home Systems in Developing Countries, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Brownstein, Carrie R.: Considering Other Consumers: Consumption of Atlantic Herring by Marine Mammals in the Gulf of Maine, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Bunn, Andrew: Landscape Connectivity: A Focal Species Approach Using Graph Theory., 2000 (Box 3)
  - Buppert, Gregory D.: Forestry for Biodiversity Conservation: Regenerating Mahogany (Swietenia macrophylla King) in the Tropical Moist Forests of Belize, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Cable, Michelle E.: The Chesapeake Bay: A Modern Common Pool Resource, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Kimberley (Kim): Water Quantity for Instream Uses in National Parks: A Study of External Threats to Park Waters in the Southeast, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Cason, Rebecca D.: Characterization of Sedimentation and Water Quality in Lake Jeanette, NC through Physical Measures and Modeling, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Cheeseman, Ted: Analysis of the Impact of Protected Area Establishments on Deforestation in Caribbean Guatemala, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Clark, Heidi: Alternative Fuel Vehicles and Corporate Decision Making: A Cost Comparison Study of Duke Energy Options, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Cooper, James (Jim): Spatial Variation in the Distribution of Epigaeic Arthropods in Southeastern Pine Forests, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Craig, Nathan: Carolina Piedmont Reservoir Shoreline Stabilization and Horticulture Guide, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Desmarais, Anne: Designing a Conservation Portfolio for the North Carolina Sandhills, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Dierkers, Gregory J.: An Evaluation of Transportation Strategies for Research Triangle Park, North Carolina, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Engler, Cristina: Soil Characteristics of Duke Stormwater Improvement and Wetland Restoration Site, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Fagan, Christopher T.: Cultural and Economic Constraints to Land Use In Paso Caballos, Laguna Del Tigre National Park, Guatemala, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Fiori, Cristina W.: The Palmetto-Peartree Preserve in Eastern North Carolina: An Ecotourism Feasibility Study, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Fisher, Jeff: Guidance for Program Directors in the Latin American Caribbean Region of The Nature Conservancy, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Foulks, Guy B.: Involving Immigrant Communities in Ecotourism: Case Study of the Baltimore Community in Amazonian Per, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Francisco, Alex: The Sorption Characteristics of the Water Tracer Rhodamine WT onto Various Subsurface Media, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Friedrichs, Gillian C.: Effectiveness of Water Quality Monitoring Designs: Decision-Making Under the Clean Water Act, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Goldman, Rebecca L.: The Etiology of Menhaden Sores: Temporal Spatial and Environmental Correlates, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Gomberg, Samuel (Sam): A Comparative Analysis of Commercial Net Fishing in Three States, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Gouldman, Carl C.: Acoustic Behavior of Pinfish (Lagodon Rhomboides), 2000 (Box 4)
  - Grau, Xavier: Managing Water Scarcity: A Case Study in Northeastern Spain, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Greiner, Sara Niven: Effect of Atrazine on Mammary Gland Development in Rats, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Griffin, Jay: An Ahupua‘a Assessment and Monitoring Program to Help Malama Hanalei Ahupua‘a, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Hale, Christopher L.: A Plan to Reduce Physical Damage to Coral and Algal-Vermetid Reefs in Bermuda, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Hall, Deborah J. Wojcik: The Coastal North Carolina Connecting Point: A Web-Based Information and Communication Tool for Citizens, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Hasinak, Kimberly A.: Predicting Nutrient Pollution in the Neuse River Basin Using Economic Models of Urbanization, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Henkels, Jamie L.: A Comparative Study of Water Quality and Quantity in Three Subbasins of the Yadkin River Basin, North Carolina, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Hesterman, Avishai (Avi): A Photographic Primer to Southern Appalachian Old-Growth Forests, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Hoert, Megan Erin: Creating the Urban Toolshed: A Case Study of Durham Children's Perceptions of Nature and Neighborhood, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Holmes, Zakiya: The Effect of Loblolly Pine (Pinus taeda) Log Decomposition on Soil Nutrients, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Jacobs, Heather E.: Landuse Effects on Streamflow in a Southern New Jersey Watershed, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Kade, Tyson Clinton: The Natural and Social Science Implications of Bluefin Tuna Migrations off North Carolina, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Kelly, Sheryl J.: A Public Beach and Coastal Waterfront Access Handbook for Local Governments, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Kenny, Shannon C.: An Evaluation of the Air Transportation Industry as a Candidate for EPA's Sustainable Industry Program, 2000 (Box 4)
  - Kintsch, Julia Alexandra: An Assessment of Representative-Based Conservation in the Amphibolite Mountains, North Carolina, 2000 (Box 4)